# **Emil Reji**

## **Profile**

I'm a full stack Software Engineer based in the Greater New York City Area. I am a co-creator of Stagehand Framework, a drop-in service for automatically deploying and managing review apps for front end applications. I have experience in a variety of technologies including, but not limited to the Ruby and JavaScript Ecosystems. I also have extensive experience working with cloud environments such as AWS, Docker, Github Actions, etc.

# **Professional Experience**

# Co-Creator, Software Engineer, Stagehand-Framework

08/2020 - present

https://stagehand-framework.github.io/ ☑

- Co-Created Stagehand, an open-source drop-in solution that automates review apps for frontend applications
- Designed and implemented the AWS infrastructure using a Cloudfront CDN, IAM Permissions, Cloudformation Automation, Lambda@Edge Functions, S3 Buckets, and EC2 Instances
- Used Github Actions to automate review app creation and tear down in response to Github events
- Used service workers and other client side code to implement a dashboard for the review app users while simultaneously solving our complex routing issues
- Created an npm package to provide a simple CLI that pulls together Stagehand's architecture
- Co-authored documentation for the npm package
- Co-authored Stagehand's case study https://stagehand-framework.github.io/ ☑
- Collaborated daily with the rest of Stagehand's remote team

# Software Engineer, Self-Employed

11/2018 - 08/2020

- Built a variety of projects including but not limited to the ones listed below
- A ticket tracker app using Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL, and RSpec
- A trello clone app using Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL, React, and Redux
- An airline routes app using React

### **Software Engineer, Senior Associate, Infosys**

09/2018 - 08/2020

- Worked as a tester and a developer using Java, Spring, Oracle, SQL, Python, Angular, Jenkins, Agile, etc.
- Was selected as part of Infosys's #FlyingHigh Associate Success Stories
- Worked remotely across multiple time zones world wide

#### **Skills**

#### **Back End**

Node.js, Express, Ruby, Ruby on Rails, Sinatra, SQL, MongoDB, REST API's, GraphQL, Webhooks, Java

#### **Front End**

JavaScript (ES6), React, Redux, HTML/CSS, Gatsby, Next.js, jQuery

#### Cloud

AWS, Digital Ocean, Heroku, Vercel

#### Tooling/Other

Git/Github, Docker, Jenkins, Agile Development

#### **Education**

# Bachelors of Science in IT, Minor in Computer Science,

2014 - 2018

Montclair State University

• GPA of 3.725 on a 4.0 scale

# **Information Security Certificate,**County College of Morris

2016 - 2017